But I'm amazed you were able to come back alive after seeing that thing.
To be expected of my student, I guess.
That's...
But rules are rules.
You're expelled.
Master-
Al.
The trains are still running.
Go home.
Thanks... for everything.
I've still got a lot of years ahead of me
Kono omoi wo keshiteshimau niwa
To just erase these feelings?
Mada jinsei nagai desho?
I want to go back and finish
Yarinokoshiteru koto
The things that I've yet to finish.
Yarinaoshite mitai kara
I was supposed to be chasing after my ongoing dream,
Yume no tsuzuki oikaketeita hazu nanoni
Yet I faltered over others while walking this thin, winding path.
Magarikunetta hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
It's not that I want to return to those days.
Ano koro mitainitte modoritai wake ja nai no
I'm searching for the sky I lost.
Nakushitekita sora wo sagashiteru
Don't make that sad face, as if you've fallen victim.
Wakatte kuremasu youni
As if you want people to pity you.
Gisei ni natta youna kanashii kao wa yameteyo
Tears aren't the end of your sins.
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
You have to bear them painfully, forever.
Zutto kurushiku seottekunda
Who are you waiting for in the maze of emotions,
Deguchi mienai kanjoumeiro ni
Where you can't even see the exit?
Dare wo matteruno?
I want to blurt it out more justly,
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta youni
Just like how I wrote it in my white notebook.
Motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
What do you want to run from?
Nani kara nogaretainda
That thing called "reality"?
Genjitsu tte yatsu?
I just want to scream out,
Kanaeru tame ni ikiterundatte
"I'm only living to fulfill my wish." Can you hear me?
Sakebitaku naru yo kikoeteimasuka?
I can't take the safe way out of everything.
Bunan ni nante yatterarenaikara
I don't even have a place to return to.
Kaeru basho mo nai no
I'm always thankful for everyone's kindness,
Yasashisa ni wa itsumo kansha shiteru
That's why I want to become stronger. (I'm on the way)
Dakara tsuyoku naritai (I'm on the way)
This is reminding me of the old days.
Natsukashiku naru
This pain is all right with me.
Konna itami mo kangei jan
Beasts of Dublith
Drop by if you're ever in the neighborhood.
But we're...
Idiot!
If you aren't in a master-student relationship anymore,
it means that from now on,
you're going to treat each other as individuals.
What's holding you back?
Dammit!
Al! What did we come to Dublith for?
Mr. Sig, we're going to head back!
Don't let her kill you.
Master!
What did you come back for?!
Who are you calling Master?!
You guys aren't my students anymore!
Go home already!
Master!
We came here to find clues on how to get our bodies back.
We can't go back with nothing.
Go home!
We won't!
Morons...
You didn't see the truth, did you, Al?
No. I have no idea what you mean...
Maybe you lost your memories due to shock.
How about we try retrieving your memories?
You had your whole body taken.
There's no way you didn't see it.
I get it!
You and I only had parts of our bodies taken, so if it's based on how much we paid, Al should know the most of the truth!
So if we can get my memories back, we might find a clue on how to get our bodies back...
But memories of that thing, huh?
That thing, huh?
Huh? Could this be bad?
More like... extraordinary?
Yeah, you could call it that.
Your mind might explode...
If you screw up, it could destroy you...
But if it'll let us find a clue...
I want to do it!
Fine.
Let me ask a friend of mine how to regain one's memories.
But before that, let's eat.
You'd better help out.
Yes, ma'am!
No doubt about it. That's the guy who affixed a soul.
East City
Eastern Headquarters
You'll be working in Central starting next week.
Yes, sir.
It'll become quiet around here.
You were quite the flashy one.
Not anywhere near as flashy as you were in your prime, sir.
I was able to relax because you worked so hard.
But I also learned a lot from all of those jobs you gave me.
Check.
I was finally able to beat you.
Let's call this victory a parting gift.
General.
I'd also like to ask for another gift.
Sgt. Major Kain Fuery.
Warrant Officer Vato Falman.
2nd Lt. Heymans Breda.
2nd Lt. Jean Havoc.
Lieutenant Riza Hawkeye.
The five of you will be transferring to Central with me.
I won't take any complaints.
Come with me!
Colonel, I can't.
I just recently found a girlfriend.
Break up with her.
Again?!
Your wounds haven't even healed yet.
Master...
I'm so happy to see you're well.
I heard rumors about you going around killing State Alchemists.
I understand your resentment.
The ones who annihilated our village were State Alchemists.
But all revenge does is give birth to more revenge.
A futile chain like that must be stopped immediately.
You must persevere.
Sorry to interrupt.
Whoa, he really was here!
An Ishbalan with a cross scar on his forehead.
We're splitting the prize money like we agreed, Mr. Yoki.
Huh? Where's Mr. Yoki?
Hey!
What's this all about?
You had nowhere to go, so we treated you like family-
Shut up!
Don't go comparing me with you Ishbalans!
I'm going to rise again!
I'm going to keep rising and rising,
and eventually get rid of that damned Edward Elric!
Now you two, please do your thing.
Seems I'll only bring trouble while I'm here.
You're an obedient one.
Y-You bastard! What did you do?!
I'll give you some time to pray to God.
G-God? You seriously think I believe-
Wait!
Stay away!
I-I was wrong!
Please spare my life!
I'll follow you forever!
Are you going?
You'll sadden your brother.
There's no going back for me.
Here he comes.
We were waiting for you, guest.
"We know your secret."
"Come to Devil's Nest."
Are you the ones who know this "secret"?
We sure are. We know quite a lot.
I also want to know my own secret.
Then it's settled.
Follow me.
But my master taught me not to follow strangers.
How old are you?
Fourteen.
If you're fourteen, shouldn't you be able to make your own decisions?
You can't be saying things like "master taught me" forever.
I see! I have to make my own decisions then, huh?
That's right!
So come with-
So I decided to tie you guys up and beat the secrets out of you.
So in the end, you chose force.
I'm coming in!
Y-You're inside-
Hey, stay put!
How does it feel to have your body controlled from the inside?
Even if you do this, you can't stop my movements completely!
You're right. But...
As long as I can restrict your movements just a bit...
We can win the fight.
Did I hurt you?
I hit my head.
Giving us trouble...
Who are you guys...
They're chimeras.
My henchmen.
Wow, that's so cool! You really are empty.
I'm Greed.
Let's try to get along.
What are you guys, really?
You were lying about being chimeras, right?
There's no way chimeras can talk!
There's no way "there's no way".
Since this girl who's inside you right now is a chimera that was transmuted with a snake.
And Loa, who's behind me... What are you again?
A cow?
Yes.
Other than that, we've got a lizard and a crocodile.
The guy you fought earlier takes a piss with one leg up.
I do not!
You're a dog?
Yeah. It's pretty useful.
No way...
That can't be true!
And besides, who are you going to say performed the transmutation successfully?
The army.
No way...
Anyway, it just means there's a flip side to this world that society doesn't know about.
On a different note, I'm not a chimera.
I'm a homunculus.
Homunculus?!
You've heard of them, haven't you?
Humans that were created artificially.
That's what I am.
Homunculus?
It's another name for an android.
But it's said in the book that you're not allowed to create humans.
You're lying!
I've never even heard of anyone creating a homunculus!
Geez...
Let me show you some proof.
W-What did you do that for?!
That's one death for me.
No way...
Do you understand now?
There's no way "there's no way".
Besides, aren't you living proof of that?
An existence with a soul and no body.
How did you...
I know just about everything that goes on in this other world.
Let's get to the point.
How does it feel to be immortal with just a soul?
Transmuting a soul and affixing it to another object.
If you do it correctly, that person can gain eternal life.
Am I wrong?
I'm Greed.
I'm greedy,
so I want money, women, status, fame, and everything else in this world!
And I want eternal life!
But aren't you already immortal?
I was made pretty durable,
so I've been alive for almost two hundred years.
But I'm not quite immortal.
Now, I've told you my secret.
It's your turn.
Tell me the secret to that body.
You should spill it.
You don't want to be taken apart and dissected, do you?
It's impossible.
I don't have any memories of when I became like this,
and I'm not the one who performed the transmutation.
I don't know anything.
Then what about the guy who did it?
We can ask him.
That's...
Where the heck did Al disappear to?
I don't mind telling ya.
If you tell us his secret, that is.
Brother!
I would never have expected you to get kidnapped.
Brother, this guy's a homunculus!
Homunculus?
Hey, don't go blowing my secret!
So he might have a hint on how to get our bodies back!
Tattoo of Ouroboros.
That's how it is.
It would have been easier if we could have just settled things with the armor boy.
If you're buddies with them,
why don't you just ask them yourself?
"Them"?
There were people with that tattoo at Research Laboratory 5.
And there, I met a guy who had
his soul affixed to a piece of armor.
Seriously?
Well, for certain reasons,
I can't really do that.
So let's discuss this.
You two want to get your bodies back, right?
I'll teach you how to create a homunculus.
And in exchange, you teach me how to transmute a soul.
It's called equivalent exchange.
But seriously...
Is there even a need to get your body back?
Personally, I think that body can be somewhat useful.
No, it's not!
You think so?
You don't get hungry,
you don't get sleepy, you don't get tired.
Sounds awesome to me!
Cut... The...
...Shit!!!
Useful?! Awesome?!
You don't know anything,
and yet you're spewing all this bullshit?!
How to transmute a soul?!
You're not getting an ounce of it from me!!!
If you're a villain, I'll beat you up, smack you,
punch the information out of you and snatch it!!
In other words, I get all and you get nothing!
There's no need for equivalent exchange when dealing with a villain!!!
Guess we have to use force again.
Don't kill him.
Fine, fine.
I met a guy on death row who was a lot faster than you!
Next.
Loa, take the armor boy with you.
We'll take him apart and dissect him.
Roger.
H-Hey!
Wait!
Useless.
With a steel sword like that, you can't even add a scratch to this ultimate shield!
Your head's wide open!
Oww... that hurt.
If I was an ordinary human,
I'd need to go to the hospital for this.
Yeah, but you're not really ordinary at all.
Well, my body is normal,
but I've got a little bit of regeneration, and I have the ultimate shield.
Get it now?
You can't beat me.
It'd be smarter to just make the trade.
Oh, you're one of those people, aren't you?
You don't care if you get covered in wounds,
but if your relatives get hurt,
you can't take it and lose your cool.
How foolish.
You're going to let your strong feelings take over like that and lose important information and your brother?
I'll go get my brother back after I beat your ass.
Your regeneration ability isn't endless, right?
As long as I keep hitting the part of you that's flesh, then...
My bad, sorry for going easy on you.
This turns me into an ugly guy,
so I don't really like to show people.
Didn't I say so?
You won't even be able to scratch me.
I found this in the back alley of West Street.
Al disappeared... and now Ed, too.
Those idiots! I may even have to make them students again and teach them about taking care of personal belongings!
I've got it!
I heard someone who looks like Ed went into a bar called Devil's Nest.
You dead?
Good! Kids should be lively.
No matter how many times you try, you can't win.
How about you tell me the secret now?
Thanks for that.
The blood that was all up in my head went away, and I can think clearly now.
That's my mechanic for ya.
It still moves after all this.
You're still going to resist?
Let this put you to sleep!
I'm solid, aren't I?
That's weird...
So what?!
What, don't you have anything else?!
What the hell... did you do to my shield....
It's simple if you think about it.
You said you're a homunculus, but if your body is normal, that means a third of your body is made up of carbon.
Depending on how the carbon atoms are combined, the toughness can range from a pencil tip's to a diamond's.
If you know that much, then it's all a matter of alchemy.
Good!
Otherwise, it wouldn't be fun!
And now, I just figured something out!
You can't harden and regenerate at the same time!
My first impression of you was that of a reckless idiot.
But how many more times can you attack me with that body?
Hi, coming in.
M-Master!
You dumbass!!!
You don't even care enough to put away a single broomstick?!
I-I'm sorry!
Looks like you gave my boys quite a bit of trouble.
Master! He's...
I know.
I could hear you all the way from the hallway.
Come on, give me a break.
I don't really like fighting women-
What... the hell are you?!
A passing...
...housewife!!!
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
Do you remember it from that day?
Nee kimi wa oboeteimasuka
We made a promise and a vow while the early summer wind circled us.
Yakusoku chigiri shoka no kaze ga tsutsumu
And we clung close together.
Futari yorisotta
Your forced smile
Muri na egao no ura
Holds elongated shadows.
Nobita kage wo kakumau
I pretend not to notice and continue on.
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei wo erabu
All the while waiting for you to deliver some news at the table.
Teeburu no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
Empty nights, mornings that will never arrive,
Kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
I could see them from a mile away.
Zenbu wakattetanda
Say, the sky we saw that day, the scarlet sky.
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora wo
I'm sure you'll remember it one day.
Nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
While holding the promise we couldn't keep,
Hatasenakatta yakusoku wo idaite
We take our first steps down our own paths.
Futari arukidasu
Those who are strong are destined to yield to ones who are far stronger.
But their souls will not lose as long as they have pride.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Those Who Lurk
Underground
Episode 14, Those Who Lurk Underground.
There's more than meets the eye.